Sigmund Freud Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1871-1996 (Box 14-44)
  - Zweig, Arnold See also Container 135, same heading
    - 1929-1933
    - 1934
    - 1935-1937
    - 1938-1939, undated
  - Zweig, Stefan, 1908-1938, undated
  - Unidentified, by Freud
    - Originals
      - 1885, 1899-1914
      - 1916-1928
      - 1929-1932
      - 1933-1938, undated
    - Photocopies and transcripts
      - 1887-1922
      - 1923-1929
      - 1930-1935
      - 1936-1939, undated
- Subject File, 1856-1988 (Box 45-50A)
  School, university, and military records; patient case files and record book; calendars; notes and notebooks; birth, citizenship, and marriage certificates; biographical data; birthday greetings; condolence letters; photocopies of book annotations and marginalia; financial and estate records; wills; and clippings and other printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization or institution, subject, or type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Accounts and receipts, 1886, 1931 (Box 45)
  - Addresses written in Freud's hand, 1923, undated
  - Allgemeines Krankenhaus, Vienna, Austria, patient case files
    - Originals
      - Set A, 1881-1883 See Oversize
      - Set B, 1881-1883 See Oversize
    - Photocopies, 1883-1885, undated
    - Stone, Irving, research collection
      - Cover letter, 1988
      - Krankengeschichten, 1880-1890
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
        - Folder 3
      - Transcripts, 1880-1890
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
  - Annotations and book marginalia written by Freud, photocopies from the New York Psychiatric Institute Library, New York, N.Y., undated
    - Section A
      - Authors A-F
      - Authors K-Z
    - Section B
      - Authors B-J
      - Authors K-W (Box 46)
    - Sections C
    - Sections D
  - Announcement of new address, Berggasse 19, Vienna, Austria, 1891
  - Anzeiger der K. K. Gesellschaft der Ärzte in Wien, 1886-1887
  - Beer, “Doctor,” Freud's comments on case, 1905
  - Bellevue Sanatorium, Kreuzlingen, Switzerland, patient case files
    - Biedermann, Clara, 1883-1943
    - Ehrenfeld, Gustav, 1894-1896
    - Eim, Gustav, 1892-1894
    - Ellissen, Julie, 1881-1891
    - Flesch, Regina, 1909-1911
      - Folder 1
      - Folder 2
    - Friedmann, Oskar
      - 1910-1938
      - 1910-1912, 1933 (Box 47)
    - Glück, Amalie, 1888-1889
    - Kern, Elise, 1892-1896
    - Linder, Emma, 1884-1886
    - Redlich, Kurt von, 1893-1916
    - Schweinburg, Olga, 1888-1899
      - 1888-1899
      - 1893-1894
      - 1894
  - Biographical listing, Das geistige Wien, 1893
  - Birth certificates, 1856, 1886, 1938
  - Birthday celebrations
    - 1916
    - 1926
      - Autograph book
      - Correspondence and tributes
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
        - Folder 3
        - Folder 4
        - Folder 5
    - 1931 (Box 48)
    - 1936
      - Folder 1
      - Folder 2
    - 1937
  - Books
    - Advertisements, undated
    - Inscriptions and related correspondence, 1877-1911, 1922-1939, 1967, 1973, undated
  - Calendar books
    - 1916
    - 1917
    - 1918
  - Citizenship certificate, Vienna, Austria, 1908
  - Clark University, Worcester, Mass., photographs, 1904-1909
  - Contracts with publishers, 1905-1910, 1939
  - Death and funeral, 1939
    - Condolences
      - Letters
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
        - Folder 3
      - Telegrams
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
    - Draft of death notice written by Freud during 1920s, undated
    - Obituary notice, Royal Society, London, England, 1940
    - Oration by Ernest Jones and clippings, 1939 (Box 49)
  - Estate records, 1940
  - Goethe Prize, 1930, 1953
  - Haberl, Ernest, case, 1922-1923, with letters from Anna Freud to Ernest Jones, 1954-1956
  - Heredity questionnaire, undated
  - Identity cards
    - Budapest, Hungary, 1918
    - Vienna, Austria, with an image of Freud and a passport photograph of another individual, 1935
  - Immigration to London, England
    - Bonaparte, Marie, Princess, draft of letter to French consul, Vienna, Austria, 1939
    - Clippings, 1938
    - Refugee tax and moving arrangements, 1938
    - United States State Department cables, 1938
  - Insurance declaration, undated
  - Internationalen Psychoanalytischen Vereinigung, 1908-1918, undated
  - Internationaler Psychoanalytischer Verlag, 1937, undated
  - Invoice, 1933 See Container 29, Grinker, Roy
  - Jewish Year Book-1939, 1939
  - Kaiserlich Königliches Allgemeines Krankenhaus, Vienna, Austria See Container 45, Allgemeines Krankenhaus
  - Leopoldstädter Communal-Real-und Obergymnasiums, Vienna, Austria
    Partially available on microfilm. Shelf No. 18,677
    - 1866-1873
    - 1866-1874
    - 1868-1873
  - Der Mann Moses und die monotheistische Religion
    - List of persons sent copies, undated
    - Reviews of English translation, 1939-1941
  - Marriage certificate, 1886
  - Medical certificate, 1919
  - Menu autographed by admirers and associates, undated
  - Military records
    - Originals, 1886-1887 See Oversize
    - Photocopies, 1885-1888 See Oversize
  - New Year's Day statement, 1897
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings
    - Photocopies and originals See also Oversize
      - 1873-1901
      - 1902-1911
      - 1912-1926
      - 1926-1939, undated
    - Transcripts of excerpts from Viennese newspapers, 1886-1911 (Box 50A)
  - Nobel Prize, 1928-1938, 1954, undated See also Container 54, Transcripts of Nobel Prize proposals
  - Österreichischen Monatschefte, advertising broadside mailed by Freud, undated
  - Patients
    - Case files See Container 45, Allgemeines Krankenhaus; Containers 46-47, Bellevue Sanatorium
    - Diagnosis, undated
    - Notes, 1909, undated See also Oversize
    - Record book, 1896-1899
    - Referral, undated
  - Pocket notebooks See also Oversize
    - 1901, Jan.-Sept.
    - 1901, July-1903, Aug.
    - 1903, Sept.-1904, July
    - 1904, July-1905, June
    - 1905, June-1906, May
    - 1906, May-Dec.
    - 1907, Sept.-1908, June
    - 1908, July-1909, Mar.
    - 1909, Apr.-1910, Sept.
    - 1910, Sept.-1912, Oct.
    - circa 1913-1915
    - 1920s-1930s
    - 1925
    - 1930s
  - Prescriptions by Freud
    - Originals, 1887, 1910, 1917-1919, 1928, 1935
    - Photocopies, 1889-1935
  - Psychoanalytic congresses, announcements and photograph, 1908-1911
  - Putnam Camp, Keene Valley, N.Y., transcript of logbook signed by Freud, 1909
  - Royal Society, Freud's reception and signing of the charter book, 1938, with letter from the society's librarian to K. R. Eissler, 1958
  - Tenants' petition signed by Freud, 1924
  - University records
    - Applications
      - As lecturer, 1885
      - As student, 1873 See Oversize
      - For travel stipends, 1876, 1885
    - Appointment certificates, 1877, 1885, 1902, 1920
    - Catalogs
      - 1886
      - 1888-1889
    - Certificate of classes taken, 1879 See Oversize
    - Miscellany, 1878-1936
  - Veterinary bills, 1938
  - W. W. Norton Co., agreement on translation rights, 1933-1935
  - Wiener Psychoanalytische Vereinigung, 1910-1938
  - Wills, 1919, 1935, 1938
  - Zentralblatt für Psychoanalyse, undated
- Writings, 1877-1985 (Box 50A)
  Writings by Freud, including holograph manuscripts, typescripts, galley proofs, printed publications, and photocopies.
  Arranged chronologically largely by year of first publication and therein according to the bibliographic sequence established by James Strachey in Indexes and Bibliographies, volume 24 of The Standard Edition of the Complete Psychological Works of Sigmund Freud (London: Hogarth Press and Institute of Psycho-analysis, 1974) and, for works published after 1974, by Ingeborg Meyer-Palmedo and Gerhard Fichtner, Freud-Bibliographie mit Werkkonkordanz (Frankfurt am Main: S. Fischer Verlag, 1989). See Oversize.
  - Writings (Container 50A) See Oversize (Box 50A)
- Supplemental File, 1765-1998 (Box 50B-111)
  - Subject File, 1765-1998 (Box 50B-67)
    Writings, correspondence, lists, chronologies, bibliographies, inventories, notes, exhibit catalogs, invitations and programs, genealogical data, obituaries of Freud's associates, auction lists, medical notes, reviews of Freud's published writings, map and chart, newspaper clippings, and printed matter concerning Freud's life and work. Most of the material is dated after Freud's death.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of writer or collector, topic, or type of material and therein chronologically.
    - Adams, Leslie See Container 60, Grimm, Otto (Box 50B)
    - Andersson, Ola
      - Correspondence concerning “Frau Emmy von N.” (Fanny von Sulzer Warder Moser), 1960-1965, 1977, undated, (2 folders)
      - “The Etiology of Psychoneuroses and Some Related Themes in Sigmund Freud's Scientific Writings and Letters, 1886-1896,” undated
      - “Lebensgeschichte von Mentona Moser,” undated
        Available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 19,237
    - Andreas-Salomé, Lou, publication by Ernst Pfeiffer of correspondence with Freud
      - Correspondence, 1956-1967
      - Miscellany, 1967, undated (Box 51)
      - Photocopies and transcripts of Freud letters, 1912-1935
      - Reviews, 1966-1967
    - Augenfeld, Felix
      - Correspondence proposing an exhibit of Freud's antiques, 1960-1961
      - Drawing of Freud's chair, undated
      - Floor plan of Freud's London, England, study and sketch of display cabinets, 1973, undated See also Oversize
    - Bach, Zellig, Freud's relation to the Yiddish Scientific Institute (YIVO), Vilna, Poland, 1984
    - Berliner Psychoanalytisches Institute, Berlin, Germany, bulletins, 1927-1935, 1954-1955, 1964-1966
    - Bibring, Edward, and Ernst Kris, regarding publication of Freud's collected works, undated
    - Blomeyer, Rudolf, “Signorelli-Analyse,” 1970, undated
    - Blüher, Hans, comments about Freud, 1912
    - B'nai B'rith lodge, Vienna, Austria, lists of lectures, undated
    - Bonaparte, Marie, Princess
      - Clippings and tear sheets regarding Freud, 1939-1940, (2 folders)
      - Freud letters copied for Anna Freud
    - Boven, W., notes on meeting of the Wiener Psychoanalytische Vereinigung, 1920, May 5
    - Breuer, Josef, page proofs of “Theoretisches,” Studien über Hysterie, 1894
    - British internment of German psychoanalysts, 1940
    - Brüel, Olaf, articles, 1945-1954
    - Brun, Rudolf, “Sigmund Freuds Leistungen auf dem Gebiete der organischen Neurologie,” 1935
    - Büttner, Peter, “Freud und der Erste Weltkrieg,” doctoral dissertation, 1975, (1 folder) (Box 52)
    - Centenary of Freud's birth
      - American Psychoanalytic Association, 1955-1956
      - Articles, editorials, and radio broadcasts, 1956
      - Boehm, Felix, statement, photographs, and clippings, 1956
      - Committee minutes, bulletins, and report, 1955-1956
      - Correspondence, 1955-1957, (2 folders)
      - Exhibit material
        - Items arranged according to a numeric scheme, 1873-1940, 1955-1956, undated See also Oversize, (3 folders)
        - Lists, circa 1956
        - Miscellany, 1900-1931, 1956-1959, undated See also Oversize
        - Photographs and drawings, 1911-1955, undated See also Oversize
        - Printed matter, 1907-1936, undated See also Oversize
      - Invitations, programs, and lists, 1955-1956, (2 folders) (Box 53)
      - New York Academy of Medicine, New York, N.Y., exhibit guest book and catalog, 1956
      - Publications, 1956-1957, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 54)
    - Central Archives for the History of the Jewish People, Jerusalem, Israel, unidentified biographical sketch of Freud, circa 1960
    - Cremerius, J., “Siegmund Freud zu seinem 10. Todestage,” 1949
    - Donoghue, Arthur K., translation of Freud's cocaine papers, 1961-1962, (2 folders)
    - Drob, Sanford, “Freud and the Chasidim: Redeeming the Jewish Soul of Psychoanalysis,” 1989
    - Du, issue featuring Freud, 1951
    - Eckstein, Jacob, transcript of album with poem by Freud, 1898-1929
    - Einstein, Albert
      - Letter to [?] Ehrmann, photocopy and transcript, 1953
      - Transcripts of Nobel Prize proposals including one regarding Freud, 1918-1954 See also Container 50, Nobel Prize
    - Eissler, K. R., explanation of a letter written by Freud to Judith Rie Rosenberg on 1928, Apr. 19; See also Container 35, Krafft, Margaret R.
    - Fagg, C. C., correspondence and essays sent to Ernest Jones, 1923, 1956
    - Fichtner, Gerhard, guides to Freudiana
      - “Addressen der Fliess-Briefe,” undated
      - “Die Bibliothek Sigmund Freuds nach den vorhandenen Verzeichnissen,” 1980, (4 folders)
      - “Freuds Lebensdaten,” 1979, (2 folders) (Box 55)
      - “Freuds Patienten”
      - “Konkordanz der Briefe von and an Sigmund Freud,” 1982
        - Teil I: “Chronologisches Verzeichnis”
        - Teil II: “Verzeichnis der Briefwechsel”, (2 folders)
      - “Literatur zur Konkordanz der Freud-Briefe,” undated
      - “Register zu den Registern von Freud-Literatur,” 1980, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 56)
      - Transcripts of patient case files, undated
    - Fichtner, Gerhard, and Albrecht Hirschmüller, “Freud's 'Katherina': Hintergrund, Entstehungsgeschichte und Bedeutung einer frühen psychoanalytischen Krankengeschichte,” 1984
    - Fliess, Wilhelm
      - Bonaparte, Marie, Princess, notes on Freud-Fliess correspondence, 1937
      - Pfennig, Richard, Wilhelm Fliess und seine Nachentdecker, 1906
      - Transcripts of Freud letters for Sigmund Freud, Aus den Anfängen der Psychoanalyse. Abhandlungen und Notizen aus den Jahren 1887-1902 edited by Princess Marie Bonaparte, Anna Freud, and Ernst Kris, 1950, (4 folders); (6 folders) (Box 57)
    - Fodor, Nancy, “Freud and the Poltergeist,” 1956
    - “Four Famous Cases: Bibliographies to Four of Freud's Cases: Dora, the Rat Man, Little Hans, and Wolf-Man,” 1968
    - Freud, Sigmund
      - Bibliographies, 1962-1965
      - Case histories, bibliography, 1968
      - Exhibit catalogs, 1956, 1972-1980
      - Family history, 1765, 1877-1968, undated See also Oversize (Box 58)
      - Lecture and student lists, University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria, undated, (2 folders)
      - Letters and publications, auction lists, 1956-1987, undated, (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 59)
      - Library
        - Freud Museum, London, England, 1975
        - New York State Psychiatric Institute, New York, N.Y., 1957, undated
      - Medical history
        - Case history by Max Schur, undated
        - Correspondence between Ernest Jones, Max Schur, and Anna Freud, 1954-1956, 1964, undated
        - Transcripts of documents from Hans Pichler, Max Schur, and others, 1923-1949
      - Museum, Vienna, Austria, catalog, 1975
      - Publications, lists of titles, dates, editions, and printings, undated
    - Friedemann, Adolf, “Was Weiss Man von der Seele? Sigmund Freud, ein Porträt,” 1967
    - Gedo, John E., and Ernest Wolf, “The 'Ich' Letters,” 1970
    - German psychoanalytic institutes, miscellaneous printed matter, 1930, 1953-1954, undated
    - Gicklhorn, Josef
      - Freud's work at the Kinder-Krankeninstitut, Vienna, Austria, undated
      - “Wissenschaftsgeschichtliche Notizen zu den Studien von S. Syrski (1874) und S. Freud (1877) über männliche Flussale,” undated
    - Gicklhorn, Josef and Renée
      - Correspondence with Suzanne Cassirer Bernfeld, K. R. Eissler, and others concerning Freud research, 1951-1965, undated, (2 folders)
      - Fragmentary research file, undated
      - Miscellaneous reports, 1953-1954, undated
    - Gicklhorn, Renée, writings on Freud's childhood, 1967, 1976, undated
    - Goldhammer, Leo, “Theodor Herzl und Siegmund Freud,” undated (Box 60)
    - Goldman, Steven, “Freuds Briefe an eine Patientin,” undated
    - Goldschmidt, Lucien, evaluation and explanation of Freud's Allgemeines Krankenhaus case files, undated
    - Gomperz, Heinrich, “Freuds Bedeutung für die Geisteswissenschaften,” 1931
    - Graphological analysis of Freud's handwriting by Dr. [?] Sendak, 1930
    - Greenwald, M., “Meetings with Sigmund Freud,” 1941
    - Grimm, Otto, correspondence with Leslie Adams concerning Freud research, 1951-1953
    - “The Growth of the Psycho-Analytic Movement,” map and chart, undated See Oversize
    - Hall, G. Stanley, register of papers at Clark University and list of Freud correspondence, undated
    - Hartel, Wilhelm August, Ritter von, to Theodor Gomperz concerning Freud, 1911
    - Hesse, Hermann, miscellaneous writings, undated
    - Hinterberger, Heinrich, catalog and circular of books and pamphlets, undated
    - Hirschmüller, Albrecht, “Eine bisher unbekannte Krankengeschichte Sigmund Freuds und Josef Breuers aus der Entstehungszeit der 'Studien über Hysterie,'” undated
    - Hirst, Albert, “Analysed and Reeducated by Freud Himself,” undated
    - Hitschmann, Eduard, autobiographical notes with references to Freud, undated
    - Hoffmann, Paul, program and publicity for his dramatic readings of Freud's writings, 1976 See also Oversize
    - Hôtel du Brésil, Paris, France, photographs, undated
    - Imago Publishing Co., circular for Band 16 of Freud's Gesammelte Schiften, undated
    - Institute of Psycho-analysis, London, England, announcement regarding a proposed English edition of Freud's writings, undated
    - International Psycho-Analytical Association, Rundbriefe, 1921-1933, (3 folders)
    - Internationalen Psychoanalytischen Kongress, programs, 1927-1939
    - Internationaler Psychoanalytischer Verlag, 1929-1937, undated
    - Jelliffe, Smith Ely, and W. A. White, inventory of letters from Freud compiled by Arcangelo D'Amore, 1977 (Box 61)
    - Jewish National and University Library, Jerusalem, Israel, list of Freud letters, undated
    - Jung, C. G.
      - Chronology of relationship with Freud compiled by Wolfgang Saurlander, undated
      - Correspondence concerning publication of letters between Jung and Freud, 1960-1963
    - Karpas, Jules L., letter regarding Morris Jacob Karpas, 1991
    - Karpe, Richard, “The Rescue Complex in Anna O's Final Identity,” 1959
    - Kastler, A., “Une lettre de Sigmund Freud à Albert Einstein sur le thème: Pourquoi la Guerre?” undated
    - Kempf, Edward J., account of interview with Freud, 1923, 1949
    - Kiel, Norman
      - Clippings re Freud, 1988-1990, undated, (2 folders)
      - Reviews of Freud's work
        - Index, undated
        - Autobiography, 1925-1936
        - The Basic Writings of Sigmund Freud, by A. A. Brill, 1938
        - Beyond the Pleasure Principle, 1923-1925, 1951
        - Bruch Stück einer Hysterie-Analyse, 1906-1909
        - Civilization and Its Discontents, 1925-1932
        - Collected works, various editions, 1906-1914, 1920-1967, (2 folders)
        - Delusion and Dream, 1907, 1917-1922, 1971
        - The Ego and the Id, 1924-1927
        - The Future of an Illusion, 1928-1929
        - A General Introduction to Psychoanalysis, 1920-1921
        - Group Psychology and the Analysis of the Ego, 1922-1926, 1974 (Box 62)
        - History of an Infantile Neurosis, 1928, 1971-1972
        - History of the Psychoanalytic Movement, 1923
        - Inhibitions, Symptoms and Anxiety, 1926-1929, 1937-1940
        - Interpretation of Dreams, 1899-1930, 1954-1956, 1974, (4 folders)
        - Introductory Lectures on Psychoanalysis, 1923, 1967, 1978
        - Jokes and Their Relation to the Unconscious, 1905-1928, 1961-1969
        - Leonardo da Vinci, A Psychosexual Study of an Infantile Reminiscence, 1910-1925, 1947, 1966
        - Letters between Freud and others, various editions, 1954-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 63)
        - Miscellaneous short writings, 1893-1933, 1954-1959, 1974, (2 folders)
        - Moses and Monotheism, 1939-1940
        - New Introductory Lectures on Psychoanalysis, 1933-1935
        - On Aphasia, 1954-1959
        - On Dreams, 1899-1914, 1952-1954, (2 folders)
        - On Psychoanalysis, 1911-1912, 1977
        - An Outline of Psychoanalysis, 1949-1950
        - The Psychopathology of Everyday Life, 1904-1918
        - The Question of Lay Analysis, 1927-1928, 1948-1952
        - Reflections on War and Death, 1918-1921, 1933-1955
        - Studies on Hysteria, 1895-1899, 1933, 1958-1959, 1972 (Box 64)
        - Thomas Woodrow Wilson: A Psychological Study, 1967-1969
        - Three Essays on the Theory of Sexuality, 1905-1915, 1921, 1950, 1963-1964
        - Totem and Taboo, 1912-1920, 1952
    - Knoepfmacher, Hugo
      - “Sigmund Freud and the B'nai B'rith,” undated
      - “Sigmund Freud at Secondary School,” undated
    - Koller, Carl, correspondence between Hortense K. Becker and Ernst Freud concerning Freud-Koller letters, 1963
    - Kratz, B., “Entwurf,” 1975
    - Kraus, Julius, “Otto Weininger--ein Plagiator?” undated
    - Krausz, Victor Wilhelm, letter concerning portrait of Freud, 1954
    - Kroiss, Gerhard, “Some Aspects of Psychoanalysis and Behaviorism,” 1980
    - Laforgue, René, “A Propos des Règles du Traitment Psychoanalytique,” 1954
    - Leo Baeck Institute, New York, N.Y., report on Freud correspondence at the institute, undated
    - Leopoldstädter Communal-Real-und Obergymnasiums, Vienna, Austria, printed matter, 1964, undated
    - Le Soldat-Szatmári, Judith, “Zur Problem von Sadismus und Masochismus,” 1985
    - Lynn, David J., “Sigmund Freud's Psychoanalysis of Albert Hirst,” undated
    - Mann, Thomas, photocopy of handwritten manuscript of “Freud und die Zukunft,” 1936
    - Maresfield Gardens, London, England
      - Elevator inspection certificate, 1942
      - Miscellaneous maps of London, 1842, 1884
      - Prints depicting the Freud residence, undated
    - McGuire, William, correspondence and lists concerning Freud and C. G. Jung, 1970-1976, undated
    - Meynell, G. G., letter concerning history of Freud publications, 1983
    - Miscellany, 1908-1916, 1932-1939, 1946-1957, 1964-1987, undated
    - Moreau, Christian, “Freud et l'Occultisme,” doctoral dissertation, 1974
    - Müller-Braunschweig, Carl
      - Streifzüge durch die Psychoanalyse, 1948
      - Zeitschrift für Psycho-Analyse, 1949-1950, (2 folders) (Box 65)
    - Obituaries of Freud associates, 1920-1984
    - Pfister, Oskar, letter to Rudolf Bruns regarding Freud, 1936
    - Pfrimmer, Theo, “Sigmund Freud Lecteur de la Bible,” doctoral dissertation, 1980, (2 folders)
    - Philatelic stamps depicting (Box 66)
      - Freud, Sigmund, 1981-1982
      - Pappenheim, Bertha (“Anna O”), undated
    - Pollack, Max, “The Moses of Freud,” undated
    - Postal, Bernard, printed matter regarding Freud and family, 1926-1956, undated
    - Schilder, [Paul?], “Prof. Freud zu Schilder's Vortrag in Sitzung Berggasse,” undated
    - Schönbauer, L., letter to K. R. Eissler with transcripts of Freud letters to Max Neuberger and Julius von Wagner-Jauregg, 1954
    - Sigmund Freud Archives, index of items, undated
    - Sigmund Freud Copyrights, archive inventory and library, 1979
    - Sigmund Freud Gesellschaft, reports, 1978-1985
    - Sigmund Freud House Bulletin, 1975-1983, (2 folders)
    - Siner, Wilhelmine, Amalia Freud's nurse, death of, 1954
    - Spielrein, Sabina, excerpts from diary concerning Freud and C. G. Jung, 1909-1910
    - Stanescu, Heinz, presentations and writings concerning Freud, 1965-1970
    - Starr, Moses Allen, regarding clash with Freud, 1912, 1935
    - Stiasny, Johann, “Praterfahrt,” 1958
    - Stoessl, Franz, transcript of letter regarding bust of Freud, 1955
    - Struck, Hermann, print portraying Freud, undated
    - Swales, Peter J., writings on Freud and Minna Bernays, 1982-1998
    - Takemura, Kotaro, photograph of sculptural rendering of Freud, undated (Box 67)
    - Thalberg, Mitzi Deutsch, biographical note, 1966
    - Trilling, Lionel, drafts of “Freud and the Crisis of Our Culture,” talk before the New York Psychoanalytic Institute, New York, N.Y., 1955-1956